Okay, so in this video,
we are just going to
introduce the resource
management knowledge area.
Now, resources, very important aspect of
your project, right?
Very important constraint on your project,
very major constraint on your project.
Now, there are two categories of resources
that you need to know about.
You have something called
physical resources and something
called human resources,
also known as team resources.
Now, physical resources are anything but
humans.
So, basically, equipment, supplies,
raw materials, facilities, machines,
these are all physical resources.
Whereas human resources are team resources,
then naturally refer to team members.
And resources are a very, very major
constraint on a project.
So remember the six constraints on a
project.
Right, you have scope, schedule,
budget, resources, quality, risk, right?
So, resources is one of those,
one of the major, major constraints on the
project, depending on the availability of
your resources, right, depending on the
availability of team members and
availability of raw materials and
machines, that has a
direct impact on your budget,
that has a direct impact
on your schedule, right?
that will also, based on resources,
you might identify risks on your project,
based on what resources are
available that can impact the
quality of the project and
the quality of the product.
So resources are very, very major,
a major, major constraint on a project.
I remember a change
in one constraint can lead
to a change in any of
the other constraints.
Now, most of this section is
going to be covering the team
resources section, most of the
resource management section.
So, just as a very quick review,
you remember the three domains.
We have the process domain, the people
domain, and the business environment domain.
So this refers to, or most of the resource
management section
refers to the people domain.
and the people domain
refers to the leadership,
the leadership area
of their talent triangle.
So remember the process, the process
domain, right, is the equivalent of the
technical project management skill set,
right?
The people domain is the leadership skill
set of the talent triangle, and the
business environment is a strategic and
business management.
So here we're talking about the
leadership, or the people.
domain.
So most of the videos, not
all, most of the videos, we're
mostly going to be concentrating
on the team resources.
But remember, though, there's also
equipment, supplies, labor, raw materials,
facilities, machines that you're using,
these are all also
resources on your project.
Now, when it comes to then your team
members, one of the key aspects as a
project manager is to create a high
performing team.
You are the project manager of your team.
You are the lead of your team.
You are the coach of your team.
You want to get the best out of your team.
Your project is only as good as your team.
So first of all, you need to get the right
people with the right skill sets.
But that's not enough.
You also want them to be working together.
If they're not working together,
they're not going to make a good team.
Just think of any sports team.
You may have the best players on your
sports team.
But if your players, if your
team members are not working
together, they're not going
to make a good sports team.
Exactly the same thing with your project
team as well.
You first want to get the
right people with the right skill
sets, but then you also want
them to be working together.
And that's entirely up to you as a project
manager to create that environment.
You want to engage your team, motivate
your team, lead your team, you're the
coach of your team, you want to get the
best out of your team.
So you want to build
your team, you want to
empower team members
to make the right decisions.
You also want to negotiate project
agreements.
We're going to talk
about these, but all of this
we're going to be talking
about in separate videos.
You want to make sure your team has the
right training to do the work.
and going on the right training at the
right time, right, the right team members
are going on the right training at the
right time.
So again, the whole thing is about leading
your team, coaching your team.
So again, just remember your project is
only as good as your team.
So you want your team members then to
collaborate, right?
It's a collaborative environment.
One of the key things about agile.
One of the key things about the agile team
is, is collaborative, right?
You want to collaborate.
You want your team members to collaborate.
So it's not just in an agile environment
either.
I haven't seen any kind of environment.
You want your team members to be working
together to collaborate.
So that's really what the resource
management section refers to.
So subsequent videos then,
we're going to be talking about all
of the other details that you
need to know for the PMP exam.
Okay.